<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<webpage title="Habitat for Humanity London">
  <style>
    h3 {
    margin-top:16px;
    margin-bottom:6px;
    }
  </style>
  <article>

    <h2 style="margin-bottom:15px;">Apply for a Habitat Home</h2>

    <a name="qualify"></a>
    <h3>Who qualifies for a home?</h3>
    The three criteria to qualify for a Habitat home are
    <ol>
      <li>need for affordable housing,</li>
      <li>ability to repay a Habitat mortgage, and</li>
      <li>willingness to partner with Habitat.</li>
    </ol>
    Need for affordable housing is defined by a family income that is below the government-set Low 
    Income Cut-Off (poverty line) for their particular region, and existing living conditions that 
    are inadequate in terms of structure, cost, safety or size. The ratio of shelter expense to 
    total income is also factored.
    <p></p>
    Ability to repay a Habitat mortgage requires that the family has a stable income sufficient to 
    cover the monthly mortgage payments and other expenses that come with home ownership.
    <p></p>
    Homeowners must demonstrate a willingness to partner with Habitat by contributing 500 hours of 
    volunteer labor ("sweat equity") towards the building of their home.
    <p></p>


    <div align="center"><img alt="" src="images/housing_header.jpg" width="387" height="151"/></div>

    <a name="choose"></a>
    <h3>How are families chosen?</h3>
    Families are chosen on the basis of the above criteria.
    We look at each family's employment records, present housing situation, and ability to carry the expense of purchasing a home.
    For more details, see our <a href="housing_assessment.pdf">Pre-Applicant Letter</a>.

    <a name="contrib"></a>
    <h3>What do families contribute?</h3>
    In addition to mortgage payments, each homeowner invests hundreds of hours of
    their time to assist in the building of their home. In return, Habitat homeowners
    are given the unique opportunity to buy a home through an interest-free mortgage.
    Thus, gaining substantial equity they would not have if renting.
    <p></p>

    <a name="apply"></a>
    <h3>How to Apply</h3>
    Contact our <a href="contact.html">Office Administrator</a> to schedule a personal 
    appointment to receive your application.
    Return the completed application to our office, so that we may
    forward it to our Family Selection Committee for review. 
    <p></p>
    Please note that the committee meets once a month, 
    therefore allow 6-8 weeks before receiving news from them concerning 
    the status of your application.
  </article>
</webpage>
