<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<webpage title="Habitat for Humanity London">
  <article>
    <h2 style="margin-bottom:15px;">Habitat Stories from London, Ontario</h2>

    <b><img alt="" src="images/icon_housing.png" style="position:relative;top:5px;"/> Family Stories</b>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="#loriworozbyt">Lori Worozbyt &amp; Family</a> (2008)</li>
    </ul>

    <b><img alt="" src="images/icon_build.png" style="position:relative;top:5px;"/> Volunteer Stories</b>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="#young">Teresa &amp; Jeff Young</a> </li>
      <li><a href="#kime">Deborah Kime</a> </li>
      <li><a href="#dianapeter">Diana Peter</a> </li>
      <li><a href="#fritzley">Natasha Fritzley</a> </li>
      <li><a href="#binder">Judy Binder</a> </li>
    </ul>

    <div class="hr"></div>

    <a name="loriworozbyt"></a>
    <h3><img alt="" src="images/icon_housing.png" style="position:relative;top:5px;"/> Lori Worozbyt's Story (Habitat Homeowner as of 2008)</h3>
    <p></p>
    <img alt="" src="images/stories_wordzbyt2.jpg" style="float:right;margin:9px;" />
    Lori Worzobyt was raised in Belmont before moving to London where she has lived for thirteen years.  She and her two children, ages 11 and 6, moved back home with her parents after the separation.  Lori has worked as an administrative assistant at the London Community Foundation since 2004.
    <p></p>
    At the beginning of 2008, Lori began to look for a place of her own to raise her family.  London was the most logical choice to live because it was here where she works, attends church, and where her children go to school.  Lori is a member of the Glen Cairn Baptist Church, and the church was generous enough to supply lunch of a few occasions to feel all of the volunteers at the build site.
    <p></p>
    While looking for a home, Lori knew that life would be different, and sacrifices would have to be made.  She had heard of Habitat For Humanity before, but had no idea that there was an active chapter in London until a coworker informed her of this.
    <p></p>
    A new chapter began for Lori and her family the day that she was notified that she had been selected as one of the four recipients of this year's Kipps Lane homes.  Lori was ecstatic.  "I was on cloud nine and wanted to tell the whole world.  Life had taken a turn for the best, and the gift that I have been given is hope.
    <p></p>
    <center><img alt="" src="images/stories_wordzbyt1.jpg" style="margin:9px;float:right;"/></center>
    Lori's friends and family were just as excited and were anxious to help out.  "They had heard of Habitat For Humanity, but they did not understand the process, or that they could come out to volunteer.  After investigating these volunteer opportunities, her friends, family and coworkers came out to help on the build site.  "They had a blast and many have said that they would like to do it again.  They were impressed with Habitat as an organization."
    <p></p>
    Anticipating the 500 hours of "sweat equity" was intimidating for Lori.  All future homeowners are required to volunteer their time to help with the build in a construction or nonconstruction format.  They can also volunteer at the ReStore.  "I was assured that a good portion of the volunteers were unskilled.  On the first day, I was made to feel welcome and that whatever contribution I could make was great.  I felt at home."
    <p></p>
    Although the majority of "sweat equity" hours must be completed by Lori, those close to her are allowed to help her to reach her sweat equity goal.  "It is humbling to see people give up their time to build, and it is encouraging to have people coming alongside you, people like my mother, father, brother-in-law, sister, coworkers and church members."
    <p></p>
    "My relationship with Habitat For Humanity has been a unique, life changing experience.  I am privileged to be a part of the build and I am grateful of the community.  I also hope to see my volunteer work with Habitat continue."
    <p></p>

    <div class="hr"></div>

    <a name="young"></a>
    <h3><img alt="" src="images/icon_build.png" style="position:relative;top:5px;"/> Teresa &amp; Jeff Young (Volunteers)</h3>
    <p></p>
    <img alt="" src="images/stories_young1.jpg" style="float:right;margin:9px;" />
    Teresa and Jeff Young reside in Ailsa Craig, a small community located just north of London, Ontario.  Jeff is self employed and Teresa works at the law firm of McKenzie Lake.  Together they have raised three children and have been active in local community activities that include children's baseball, church functions and events at the 'Crest Centre', which is an organization that provides "...quality supports to adults with mental health and, or developmental disabilities that facilitate full citizenship through personal growth and participation in all aspects of community life".
    <p></p>
    Although Teresa mentions that her father came from the construction industry, and Jeff has experience as a heavy equipment operator, this is the first time that the couple have volunteer their time to Habitat For Humanity London Inc.
    <p></p>
    "This is an opportunity to help someone...a way of giving back and helping close to home." says Teresa.  "I can't see myself going on a mission to Africa." adds Jeff.  "...and we did not know any of the volunteers outside of McKenzie Lake, but that part didn't matter.  We are here to help our community."  Jeff's personal business purchase three bricks from McKenzie Lake's own fundraiser and the proceeds of their efforts go towards this year's Habitat For Humanity London build.
    <p></p>
    "I'll never remember what was so important that I would have passed on this opportunity to help.  It does good, for a good cause."  Jeff is sincere in his statement.
    As for Teresa, her reason for volunteering is rooted in the law firm of corporate sponsor McKenzie Lake.
    <p></p>
    "Angus McKenzie is a true gentleman with a good heart, who has never forgotten his roots.  He is an inspiration because he is so community oriented.  The lawyers that I work with are all good people, and I am doing this in celebration of Senior Partner Angus McKenzie... because of who he is and his accomplishments.
    <p></p>


    <div class="hr"></div>

    <a name="kime"></a>
    <h3><img alt="" src="images/icon_build.png" style="position:relative;top:5px;"/> Deborah Kime (Volunteer)</h3>
    <p></p>
    <img alt="" src="images/stories_kime1.jpg" style="float:right;margin:9px;" />
    Deborah Kime is a happily married mother of two boys, age 11 and 13, and she holds the position of Director of Groups Sales for Global Spectrum, the parent company of the John Labatt Centre.  Outside of work, she keeps herself busy with fundraising activities and charitable work that revolves around her children.  Deborah also enjoys shopping.
    <p></p>
    At one time Deborah called England home for ten years.  She says she left for England with five boxes of junk, and came back with a husband and added to her collection of boxes.
    <p></p>
    In the past, Deborah had purchased fixtures through the ReStore.  She was introduced to the concept on volunteering on build sites when her extended family shared their experiences helping out.  This year, the John Labatt Centre became a Habitat for Humanity London sponsor when they decided to tie in their 5th year anniversary with the build.
    <p></p>
    Back in England, Deborah exercised some of her build skills while doing some renovations with her husband.  She adds '...people can surprise themselves with the skills that they have once they are given a bit of direction.'
    <p></p>
    Her career keeps her pretty busy and she wishes that could have had more time to participate at this year's build, but the experience she walked away with was very rewarding.  'At this stage in life, it is important for me to contribute something to someone else that is not for her own personal gain.'  The volunteer experience is one that she hope to be able to pass onto and share with her children.  "Our family is fortunate, and being able to give our time and energy to help someone else gain more is important."
    <p></p>
    Deborah also comments on the 'all women builds' that have taken place.  "I think the introduction of the 'All Women' builds are empowering because with some direction, they allow us to transfer our own skills to site skills."  Her favorite quote is 'Go Big or Go Home'.
    <p></p>
    In closing, Deborah would like to thank all the people behind the scenes, the churches and organizations who kindly donate lunches for the volunteers.  "The effort is high and far reaching, and this is certainly a cause worthy of people's time."
    <p></p>


    <div class="hr"></div>

    <a name="dianapeter"></a>
    <h3><img alt="" src="images/icon_build.png" style="position:relative;top:5px;"/> Diana Peter (Returning Volunteer)</h3>
    <p></p>
    <img alt="" src="images/stories_peter1.jpg" style="float:right;margin:9px;" />
    With two grown children, three grandsons and one granddaughter, Diana Peters still finds time to garden, enjoy crafting, and work on her home.  Diana also likes to travel and her most recent adventure took her to Equator.
    <p></p>
    Now retired, Diana says it was the company that she used to work for that had introduced her to Habitat For Humanity London Inc.  The company often donated doors to the ReStore, and one day Diana decided to send in a volunteer application.  This year's build is Diana's sixth with Habitat.  Diana is not stranger to volunteering her time, and helped out with other organizations such as Beavers, Cubs, Sea Cadets and amongst other activities that her children were involved in.
    <p></p>
    When Diana first decided to volunteer with Habitat For Humanity London Inc. she was not sure what to expect.  Her husband had passed away and with her children grown, she was on her own.  Diana figured it was time to learn skills that would help her to maintain her own home.  At her job, Diana sat at a desk all day, but she loved being active and the outdoors.  Reflecting on years gone by, she often wished that she had attended a school that made it more feasible for women to take trade courses.
    <p></p>
    Meeting people and the satisfaction of knowing that she has helped someone else are the things Diana enjoys most about the time she donates to Habitat.  "I have always had my own home and it is gratifying to help someone achieve their own goals."
    <p></p>
    When asked what her favorite quote is, Diana responds "Probably my daughter's answer to 'how old are you' ... 'As old as my tongue and a little older than my teeth' ... this is now what she tells her kids.
    <p></p>
    "I think people are missing out when they don't volunteer for Habitat for Humanity.  You are able to find skills that you have that you did not know you had.  The trades people and experts are very patient with you."
    <p></p>

    <div class="hr"></div>

    <a name="fritzley"></a>
    <h3><img alt="" src="images/icon_build.png" style="position:relative;top:5px;"/> Natasha Fritzley (Volunteer)</h3>
    <p></p>
    <img alt="" src="images/stories_fritzley1.jpg" style="float:right;margin:9px;" />
    Since the fall of 2007, Natasha Fritzley has been a member of the Group Sales team at the John Labatt Centre.  Originally from Barrie, Ontario Natasha and has previously resided in Miami and Houston.    She currently loves life as a single woman.
    <p></p>
    It was after Katrina hit the United States that Natasha became more familiar with what Habitat did in trying to make a difference in people's lives.  Her previous hands on experience included painting a bedroom and a ceiling, and working with carpet.  When asked if her experience at the Habitat London build site was what she expected it to be, Natasha answers "Yes", and then jokingly adds "...but I thought I would have a lot more natural ability."
    <p></p>
    What Natasha enjoyed most about being part of the group of volunteers from the John Labatt Centre, one of this years corporate sponsors, was "Contributing to a charitable organization and being able to see where the money goes, the results, and the benefits."  It is no wonder that her favorite quote is "The harder you fall, the higher you bounce."  She sees the experience as something that she can continue to do in the future with friends and coworkers.
    <p></p>
    Natasha is very grateful to Habitat for Humanity London Inc. for the opportunity to learn new skills, recognize her weaknesses, and to be able to work towards a common goal as part of a team.
    <p></p>


    <div class="hr"></div>

    <a name="binder"></a>
    <h3><img alt="" src="images/icon_build.png" style="position:relative;top:5px;"/> Judy Binder (Volunteer)</h3>
    <p></p>
    <img alt="" src="images/stories_binder1.jpg" style="float:right;margin:9px;" />
    Calling Windsor her 'hometown', Judy Binder is CMHC's (Canadian Mortgage and Housing Corporation) District Manager for Southwestern Ontario, and she is no stranger to the Habitat For Humanity London Inc. build site.
    <p></p>
    Her first experience building homes with Habitat was back in 1990 and Judy says that she has been 'hooked ever since."  Judy says that it is through the company's corporate involvement that he has been given the opportunity to be a part of the communities across Ontario.  "Without a doubt, my professional and personal perspectives have left me smitten - hook, line and sinker."  It has become an 18 year love affair for Judy's relationship with Habitat.
    <p></p>
    When asked what she most enjoys about her volunteer experience over the years, Judy notes "Watching a community come together to support the families who otherwise would not be able to build and support a home of their own.  It is a fantastic way to bond with a community, and is a great learning experience for people.  Her favourite jobs are "...framing and roofing, not insulation..." she laughs.
    <p></p>
    Her career and Habitat is her life, and she says animals, mostly dogs and cats, are her hobby.   "Habitat is as strong as the community participation.  I have to take my hat off to all of the communities who have affiliates, because they are a big part of how and why the Habitat organization is able to thrive."
    <p></p>


  </article>
</webpage>
